Daniel Richardson

Computer Programmer

BRIEF

Computer games Technology graduate (BSc Hons) currently travelling and freelancing for companies, developing a variety of programs in an expanding number of languages. Most recently I am living in India and creating a Point and object tracker using C++ and OpenCV for a science institute, IISER (Indian Institutes of Science Education and Research) so they can track fine nasal movement and cage behavior in mice & developing a multi-platform web-based application to teach kids English for a Japanese company with plans to expand to a wider audience.

I am an experienced and determined C++ programmer and have enjoyed the many opportunities to use my skills working alone or as part of a larger group with members of the same or different professions. I'm also experienced in the use of Java, Python, HTML5/JavaScript, PHP, C, shader languages and a variety of source control environments.

EXPERIENCE

IISER (Indian Institutes of Science Education and Research): Pune, India — Software Developer & Equipment technician

SEPTEMBER 2018 - AUGUST 2019

Creating a Point and object tracker using C++ and OpenCV so they can track fine nasal movement/emotions and cage behavior in mice and copulation behavior in flies. During this time, I was also tasked with using my systems knowledge to update their outdated software on a variety of their lab equipment, such as Lickometers and odour delivery units, allowing them to test a larger range of variables and have finer control over timings and effects.

Kids UP 株式会社ピーアップ: Tokyo, Japan — Android/iOS Application Developer

JUNE 2018 – CURRENT

Worked with a Japanese company to develop an app to teach their students at the schools and at home English in a fun and engaging way. I solo created the application for them for the first half a year including all the games and score saving system, we have since then ported it to work on Android, IOS and PC. Project is currently being expanded to include more languages for a wider audience.

Glasgow, Scotland richardsondaniel.co.uk richardson.daniel@hotmail.co.uk contact@richardsondaniel.co.uk github.com/RichardsonDaniel /in/danielrichardson001

SKILLS/LANGUAGES

C++ C C#

Java Swift Python

HTML JavaScript CSS

Android iOS OpenCV

OpenGL Phaser Git

Django Phaser Unreal Engine 4

AWARDS

UWS Court Medal

Most Distinguished Student

Digital Futures 2016

Honorable mention, best project award & keynote speech spot

Game Jam Winner

UWS 2015

PurpleTigerStudios: Glasgow, Scotland — *Lead back Programmer*

JUNE 2015 - AUGUST 2018

During my time at PurpleTigerStudio I was the lead back-end programmer for a statistical hockey app that we where hired to create on behalf of the Scottish ice hockey association. The Hockey app was designed to shorten the statistical analysis of hockey games, information that would usually take weeks of processing and determining would now take seconds. The app will take inputs such as matches results, penalties, timings, updates and then using this information will update the statistics on each team's page and each person's personal statistics which then each family member, attendee or participant can check in real time with the game.

iRepair: Glasgow, Scotland — Manager/Senior Technician

JUNE 2013 - AUGUST 2018

I managed staff and high-end customers daily; timetabling, hiring and firing, stock & training on a broader level. As the longest member off staff there I also have the most training/knowledge of components and repair and handle any repair the staff cannot do themselves or would be too risky for them to attempt. During this time, I fixed every major AAA mobile device on the market up until my leaving point of 2018.

EDUCATION

Computer Games Technology BSc (Hons) — University of the West of Scotland

SEPTEMBER 2012 - JULY 2017

In this degree course I learned to use various languages and technologies to design and build game systems like 2D and 3D graphics and physics, AI systems, Facial Recognition devices, web services, console systems and wireless device communication. I had the role of team leader in many group projects to gain management and leadership experience. I also have experience of pitching and presenting projects.

CERTIFICATIONS

TEFL, Master— Teaching English as a foreign language master level

Completed a TEFL master course during my final years of university so I could travel and contribute in some way to the areas I visited. This course was completely out the bounds of my usual endeavors and taught me a great deal of patience and problem solving for new tasks within different environments out of my norm. Certification allows me to teach both children and adults within schools, colleges and asylums in a variety of countries.

